# **Amit Kumar**

#### **ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT - CAPGEMINI**

Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra amitkumar92386\_od4@indeedemail.com +91-9036102947

Associate consultant with 2.2 years of experience working directly for Capgemini Pvt ltd. Looking forward to handle increasing responsibility, challenging assignment to harness my technical skills and a long-term association with an organization having dynamic work environment where my skills could be enhanced and grow in the hierarchy of the Company.

Willing to relocate to: Mumbai, Maharashtra - Kolkata, West Bengal - Bangalore Urban, Karnataka

## Work Experience

### **ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT**

CAPGEMINI

August 2016 to Present

Took ownership and provided end to end execution of all activities related to the day to day operations of the Banks production applications. Focused on service improvements, automation and cost reduction where

Focused on service improvements, automation and cost reduction where possible.

Analyzing the faults and specifying corrective measures to ensure no occurrence of out stages

Analyzing, preparing the impact analysis, test plan and test result for any changes that needs to be deployed in production.

Done development in Python. Have knowledge in Java, C++ and C.

Handle Production support activities like abend resolution and closure.

Providing break fixes and repairing of data because of incident like abends.

Tuning and monitoring the applications which include code changes.

Conducted various meetings with client, discussing on the scope of

development of requests, enhancement of approach and solve critical issues ranging to request level.

Planning and performing disaster recovery testing.

Provided with ownership and prioritization for group of Incidents, Problems or Changes and ensuring the delivery of solutions in line with the Operational

Level Agreements to deadlines and quality standards

Delivered documentation to agreed standards, on time and error free Provided out of office hours cover and support, expertise and specialized system knowledge to allow resolution of key incidents.

Trained and provided support and direction to junior support analysts Detailed knowledge of Nordea Release and Change process and procedures Taken the lead and driven engagement with all business users and understand

their issues, regardless of Seniority Reviewed the quality of Incident, Change and problem tickets before

deploying it into production.

### Associate consultant (Analyst and developer)

CAPGEMINI - Mumbai, Maharashtra

August 2016 to Present

in Python for Nordea bank project, Mumbai starting from Aug 2016 to present date.

• Worked as Queue manager using BMC Remedy tool for Nordea bank project.

### Key responsibilities:

- Took ownership and provided end to end execution of all activities related to the day to day operations of the Banks production applications.
- Focused on service improvements, automation and cost reduction where possible.
- Analyzing the faults and specifying corrective measures to ensure no occurrence of out stages
- Analyzing, preparing the impact analysis, test plan and test result for any changes that needs to be deployed in production.
- Done development in Python. Have knowledge in Java, C++ and C.
- Handle Production support activities like abend resolution and closure. Providing break fixes and repairing of data because of incident like abends. Tuning and monitoring the applications which include code changes.
- Conducted various meetings with client, discussing on the scope of development of requests, enhancement of approach and solve critical issues ranging to request level.
- Planning and performing disaster recovery testing.
- Provided with ownership and prioritization for group of Incidents, Problems or Changes and ensuring the delivery of solutions in line with the Operational Level Agreements to deadlines and quality standards
- Delivered documentation to agreed standards, on time and error free
- Provided out of office hours cover and support, expertise and specialized system knowledge to allow resolution of key incidents.
- Trained and provided support and direction to junior support analysts
- Detailed knowledge of Nordea Release and Change process and procedures
- Taken the lead and driven engagement with all business users and understand their issues, regardless of Seniority
- Reviewed the quality of Incident, Change and problem tickets before deploying it into production.

### Education

### **Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)**

Reva institute of technology and mangement

_			
$\leq$	I	н	
. )	$\sim$ 1	ш	$\neg$

BMC (2 years), C++ (2 years), JAVA (2 years), PYTHON (2 years), REMEDY (2 years)

### Additional Information

Skills:

- Python, C++, JAVA and SQL.
- Mainframe (COBOL, JCL, DB2, VSAM and CICS)
- Operating Systems (OS/390, Z/OS)
- Application Development Tools like Pycharm SPUFI, Endevor
- Basic knowledge of Hadoop
- Ticket management tool like BMC Remedy, RHINO.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office (PowerPoint, Outlook, Word, Excel)